Hands on our hearts, our foreheads touching, as we communicated through movement and music, making sense through nonsense. Bella is 83 and lives with dementia. The dance gives us a chance to find each other. How did I learn to dance with dementia? Because I'm not a dancer. And I'm not a doctor. But I've played one in the hospital. (Laughs)
Manos sobre nuestros corazones nuestras frentes tocándose nos comunicamos a través de movimientos y música creando sentido del sinsentido. Bella tiene 83 años y vive con demencia. El baile nos da la oportunidad de encontrarnos. ¿Cómo aprendí a bailar con demencia? Porque no soy un bailarín Y no soy médico. Pero interpreto a uno en el hospital. (Risas)
I'm a clown doctor. Or a medical clown. My tools are whoopee cushions, shakers (Shaker rattles) and a red nose. You know the old adage "laughter is the best medicine?" I hear that a lot. Now, at the same time, there are studies to support it, but right now, I'd like to take you behind the nose and go beyond the laughter and share a few things that I've seen skating through ICUs. In my Heelys. Size 11. Because I take medical clowning very, very seriously. (Deflating sound) (Laughter) My mentor was conducting clown rounds in the hospital when he was approached by a nurse. They needed to put a tube up the kid's nose. Kid didn't want to do it, so rather than hold the kid down, they asked my colleague if he could help. So the clown asked for a second tube and shoved it up his own nose. Kid of like this. Oh, please don't do this at home. (Laughter) Now, the kid saw this, grabbed his own tube and promptly stuck it up his own nose, kind of like this.
Soy médico payaso. O payaso médico. Mis herramientas son cojines de ventosidades, cascabeles, (Cascabel agitándose) y una nariz roja. ¿Conocen el viejo dicho: "la risa es la mejor medicina"? Escucho eso un montón. Al mismo tiempo, hay estudios que lo respaldan, pero ahora mismo, me gustaría llevarlos detrás de la nariz y más allá de la risa y compartir cosas que vi pasando por unidades de cuidados intensivos. En mis zapatones. Talla 11. Porque me tomo las payasadas médicas muy, muy en serio. (Sonido de pedorreta) (Risas) Mi mentor llevaba a cabo rondas de payasos en el hospital cuando lo abordó una enfermera. Tenía que intubar a un niño por la nariz. El niño no quería, así que, en lugar de sujetarlo, le pidieron a mi colega que si podía ayudar. Así que el payaso pidió un segundo tubo y se lo metió en la nariz. De esta manera. Y por favor, no hagan esto en casa. (Risas) Bien, el niño vio esto, agarró su propio tubo y rápidamente se lo metió por la nariz, de esta manera.
(Applause) The clowns, the nurse and the patient discovered a creative solution for their situation together. And guess what, there's research to back this up. Randomized controlled trials in Israel and Italy show that medical clowns can be as effective as tranquilizers with no side effects. In 2004, I started conducting my own clown rounds at the Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center in New York City. My colleague and I were invited to accompany a young six-year-old with the most adorable southern accent, to accompany him while he got his chemotherapy port flushed, a very uncomfortable and regular procedure. We joined him, his mom and the nurse in this tiny, closed curtain cubicle. Every medical clown encounter begins by obtaining consent from the patient. So we ask him if we can be there. He says, "Sure." We're often the one element that a child could control while they're in the hospital. So we start with a card trick, fan the deck so he can pick. But as soon as the nurse approaches with the needle to flush the port, he starts screaming and cussing like no six-year-old I'd ever heard in my life. So we say, "Hey, should we come back later?" He stops, mouth open, eyes wet with tears, face flushed pink with anger, and he smiles, "Oh no, you're fine, I want you to be here." OK. So we start playing a song, my colleague on recorder, me on whoopee cushion. The nurse approaches with the needle, and it happens again, this torrent of four-letter words. He went from playing and laughing to screaming and crying, back and forth until the procedure was complete. For the first time, I experienced this odd duality of joy and suffering. But not for the last time. See, when we're there, we're not there merely to distract or make anyone feel better per se. The medical clowns work moment by moment to create connections between the clowns, the nurse, the parent and the child. This provides a source of power or control for the child while supporting the staff with their work. I've spent over a decade bringing joy and delight to the bedsides of terminally ill children in the top hospitals in New York City. And you know what I've learned? Everyone's hurting. Staff, family, patients. The patient's in the hospital because they're hurting. The family's hurting as they navigate uncertainty, grief and the financial burdens of care. The staff is hurting, only it's more than burnout. More and more health care workers are reporting feeling overworked and overextended. Now, I'm not so naive as to suggest that the solution is to send in the clowns. (Laughter) But what if? What if the tools of medical clown arts practitioners from around the world permeated our entire health care system? In 2018, at the Healthcare Clowning International Meeting, they represented over 150 programs in 50 different countries. University of Haifa offers a formal undergraduate degree program in medical clowning. Argentina has passed laws requiring the presence of medical clowns in public hospitals at their largest province.
(Aplausos) Los payasos, la enfermera y el paciente descubrieron juntos una solución creativa para su situación. Y adivinen qué, hay evidencia científica que lo respalda. Ensayos controlados aleatorios en Israel y en Italia mostraron que los payasos pueden ser tan efectivos como los tranquilizantes, pero sin efectos secundarios. En 2004 comencé a realizar mis propias rondas de payaso en el Centro de Cáncer Memorial Sloan Kettering en Nueva York. A mi colega y a mí nos invitaron a acompañar a un joven de 6 años con el acento sureño más adorable mientras se purgaba su puerto de quimioterapia, un procedimiento muy incómodo y habitual. Nos unimos a él, a su madre y a su enfermera en este cubículo pequeño, cerrado con cortinas. Cada encuentro con payasos médicos empieza con el consentimiento del paciente. Así que le preguntamos si podíamos estar allí. Él dijo: "Claro". A menudo somos lo único que un niño puede controlar mientras está en el hospital. Empezamos con un truco de cartas, extendí la baraja para que pudiera elegir. Pero cuando la enfermera se acercó con la aguja para limpiar el puerto, comenzó a gritar y maldecir como no había oído jamás a ningún niño de 6 años. Entonces dijimos: "¿Volvemos más tarde?". Él para, con la boca abierta, ojos húmedos con lágrimas, cara roja por la ira, y sonríe: "No, está bien, quiero que se queden aquí". De acuerdo. Empezamos a tocar una canción. mi colega con la flauta, yo con el cojín de ventosidades. La enfermera se acerca con la aguja, y ocurre de nuevo, este torrente de palabras malsonantes. Él pasa de jugar y reír a gritar y llorar, ida y vuelta hasta completar el procedimiento. Por primera vez, experimenté una extraña dualidad entre alegría y sufrimiento. Pero no por última vez. Cuando estamos allí, no estamos solo para distraer o hacer que alguien se sienta mejor. Los payasos médicos trabajan en cada momento para crear conexiones entre los payasos, la enfermera, los padres y el niño. Esto proporciona una fuente de poder y control al niño mientras apoya al personal con su trabajo. He pasado más de una década trayendo alegría y deleite a las camas de niños con enfermedades terminales en los mejores hospitales de Nueva York ¿Y saben qué he aprendido? Todos están sufriendo. Personal, familia, pacientes. Los pacientes en el hospital porque están sufriendo. La familia sufre mientras navega por la incertidumbre, dolor y la carga financiera del tratamiento. El personal sufre, pero más de agotamiento. Más y más profesionales de la salud denuncian sentirse sobrecargados y extenuados. No soy tan ingenuo como para sugerir que la solución sea enviar payasos. (Risas) Pero ¿y si...? ¿Y si las herramientas de los practicantes de payasos médicos del mundo impregnaran todo nuestro sistema de salud? En 2018 en el Encuentro internacional de Payasos Médicos, había más de 150 programas en 50 países diferentes. La universidad de Haifa ofrece un programa formal de licenciatura en payaso médico. Argentina ha aprobado leyes que requieren la presencia de payasos médicos en hospitales públicos de sus provincias más grandes.
And this work affects more than the patients. It makes things better for the whole health care team. One of my favorite games to play in the hospital is elevator music. I love elevators, because they're a place where paths cross, different worlds meet. It's intimate, uncomfortably quiet and just begging for a little playful disruption. The doors close and "The Girl from Ipanema" starts playing on Hammond organ, because I keep a portable speaker hidden in my pocket. So for those used to using the silent, sterile elevator, it's a moment of surprise. Folks have permission to acknowledge or not this disruption.
Y este trabajo afecta más que los pacientes Mejora las cosas para todo el equipo médico. Uno de mis juegos favoritos en el hospital es la música de ascensor. Me encantan los ascensores, porque son un lugar donde se cruzan caminos, se encuentran diferentes mundos. Es íntimo, incómodamente tranquilo y solo ruegas por un poco de interrupción juguetona. Las puertas se cierran y "The Girl from Ipanema" empieza a sonar en el órgano Hammond porque guardo un altavoz portátil escondido en mi bolsillo. Para aquellos acostumbrados a usar el ascensor silencioso y estéril es un momento de sorpresa. La gente tiene permiso para aceptar o no esta interrupción.
The game grows with every stop, because as soon as the elevator stops, the music stops. New passengers get on, and the current passengers get to witness the new passengers -- their surprise -- as they hear the elevator music for the first time. You experience the shift of adults standing silently, strangers in an elevator, to attempting to suppress their mirth, to, "Is this a party or an elevator," filled with full-on laughter. Research conducted in Brazil, Australia, Canada and Germany confirm that the artistic interventions of medical clowns improve the work environment for the staff, beyond the elevator, and support their work administering care. Promising research in the US indicates that arts programing in the hospital can improve the work environment, leading to increased job satisfaction and better quality of care. My work has taught me how to actually be present. How to breathe in a room with a person in pain. How to connect and build trust, no matter the age, ability or illness. And how medical clowning is an excellent way of using the arts to put the care back in health care. Thanks. (Applause)
El juego crece con cada parada, porque tan pronto como el ascensor se detiene, la música para. Nuevos pasajeros se suben y los actuales pasajeros pueden presenciar a los nuevos pasajeros, su sorpresa, ya que escuchan la música de ascensor por primera vez. Experimentas el cambio de adultos de pie en silencio, extraños en un ascensor intentando reprimir su alegría, a "¿Es una fiesta o un ascensor?", llena de carcajadas. Una investigación realizada en Brasil, Australia, Canadá y Alemania confirma que las intervenciones artísticas de payasos médicos mejoran el ambiente laboral para el personal, más allá del ascensor, y apoyan su trabajo gestionando el cuidado. Una prometedora investigación en EE. UU. sugiere que incorporar arte en el hospital puede mejorar el ambiente de trabajo dando mayor satisfacción laboral y una mejor calidad en la atención. Mi trabajo me ha enseñado cómo estar de verdad en el presente. Cómo respirar en una habitación con una persona con dolor. Cómo conectar construir confianza, no importa la edad, capacidad o enfermedad. Y cómo el payaso médico es una excelente forma de usar el arte para devolver la atención a la atención médica. Gracias. (Aplausos)